Guide to the Women Writing Women's Lives Records TAM 316
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
Women Writing Women's Lives Records
1989-2008
TAM 316
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
3.5 linear feet (4 boxes)
Founded in 1990, Women Writing Women’s Lives is an ongoing seminar of about sixty women engaged in writing book-length biographies and memoirs, affiliated with the Center for the Study of Women and Society and the Center for the Humanities at the Graduate Center of the City University of New York. Members meet monthly to present work for discussion, share ideas, and hear about the work of outside presenters. The collection consists of administrative files, subject files, and notes and lectures from the group’s monthly meetings.
Women Writing Women's Lives.
Provenance
The Women Writing Women’s Lives Records were given to the Tamiment Library in January 2004 by Kathy Chamberlain, Steering Committee Chair.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
[HISTORICAL/BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE]
Founded in 1990, Women Writing Women’s Lives is an ongoing seminar of about sixty women engaged in writing book-length biographies and memoirs. Its members include academics, poets, journalists and novelists. Women Writing Women's Lives is under the aegis of the Center for the Study of Women and Society and the Center for the Humanities at the Graduate Center of the City University of New York.
Monthly meetings, planned by a Steering Committee, are arranged in order for members to present work for discussion, share ideas, and hear about the work of outside presenters.
Sources:
Women Writing Women’s Lives (WWWL) Seminar. http://web.gc.cuny.edu/womencenter/wwwl/
Scope and Content Note
The General Files consist of administrative records such as membership applications and questionnaires, financial records, and minutes of the Steering Committee meetings. Clipping and subject files on topics related to women’s biography and biographers are also included.
The Session Records contain announcements, attendance sheets, lectures and notes from the organization’s monthly meetings. Names of lecturers are indicated in the folder title.
Box IV consists of unprocessed materials.
Arrangement
I, General Files: Arranged alphabetically. II, Sessions Records: Arranged chronologically
Organized into 2 series:
I, General Files, 1989-2004
II, Sessions Records, 1991-2004
Alexander, Meena, 1951-; Bair, Deirdre; Bernikow, Louise, 1940-; Bingham, Sallie; Chase, Norah C.; Chevigny, Bell Gale; City University of New York. Center for the Study of Women and Society.; City University of New York. Graduate School and University Center.; Cook, Blanche Wiesen; DeSalvo, Louise A., 1942-; Duggan, Lisa, 1954-; Gray, Francine du Plessix.; Hertog, Susan.; Mann, Emily.; Mathews, Nancy Mowll; Moore, Honor, 1945-; Painter, Nell Irvin.; Prioleau, Elizabeth Stevens, 1942-; Women Writing Women's Lives.; Correspondence.; Lecture notes.; Minutes.; New York (N.Y.); Women biographers.; Women |v Biography
- Series I: General Files, 1989-2004.
  - Articles (mostly on Women and Biography), 1990-1997 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Attendance Lists, undated, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bernhardt, Debra: Memorial, May 1, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bernikow, Louise, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Conference, 10th Anniversary, Dec 8, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Contact Lists, 1997-2002 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Cook, Blanche Wiesen, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1993-2000 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 2001-2003 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Finances, 1991-2001 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Floppy Discs (administrative files), 1996, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Grant Proposal (New York Council for the Humanities), 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Membership Applications: A-J, 1992-2001 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Membership Applications: K-M, 1992-2001 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Membership Applications: N-Z, 1993-2002 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Membership: General, 1992-2002 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Membership Lists, 1991-1998 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Membership Questionnaire, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Membership Questionnaire, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Membership Questionnaire, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Membership Questionnaire, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Membership Questionnaire, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Membership Questionnaire, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Membership Questionnaire, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Membership Questionnaire, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Menus, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Mission Statement, Guidelines, Group Archives, 1995-2004 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - News Articles, 1994-1998 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Notes: General, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Steering Committee Business, 1991-1995 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Steering Committee Business, 1996-1999 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Steering Committee Correspondence, 1991-1995 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Steering Committee Correspondence, 1996-1999 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Steering Committee Correspondence, 2000-2003 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Steering Committee Notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Topics, 1996-2001 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Writings on Biography: General, 1989-1998 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Series II: Session Records, 1991-2004.
  - Session Records (Eunice Lipton), Oct 14, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Session Records (Liz Wood), Nov 11, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Session Records (Louise DeSalvo and Sue A. Shapiro), Dec 9, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Session Records (Anne Higonnet and Nancy Mowll Mathews), Feb 10, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Session Records (Blanche Wiesen Cook), Mar 8, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Session Records (Sallie Bingham, Ellen Chessler, Nancy Rubin), Apr 13, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Session Records (Shereen Brysac, Lisa Duggan, and Francine du Plessix Gray), May 11, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Session Records (Ellen Chessler and Gloria Ehrlich), Oct 5, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Session Records (Bell Chevigny), Nov 9, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Session Records (Norah Chase and Nell Painter), Dec 14, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Session Records (Deirdre Bair, Blanche Wiesen Cook, Francine du Plessix Gray and Aileen Ward), Jan 11, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Session Records (Christie McDonald and Nancy Pittman), Feb 8, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Session Records (Deirdre Bair, Carole Klein, and Louise DeSalvo), Mar 8, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Session Records (Sharen O’Brien, and Joan Weimer), Apr 12, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Session Records (Gail Hornstein), May 10, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Session Records (Sallie Bingham, Dorothy Helly, and Nell Painter), Oct 4, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Session Records (Joan Hendrick and Martha Saxton), Nov 8, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Session Records (Joanne Grant and Grace Hechinger), Dec 13, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Session Records (Nancy Kline and Brooke Kroegar), Jan 10, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Session Records (Deborah Baker and Thadious Davis), Feb 14, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Session Records (Harriet Hyman Alonso and Betty Caroli), Mar 14, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Session Records (Barbara Lachman and Nancy Rubin), Apr 11, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Session Records (Deirdre Bair, Blanche Wiesen Cook, and Louise DeSalvo), May 9, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Session Records (Carole Klein and Joan Mellon), Oct 3, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Session Records (Harriet Hyman Alonso, Patricia Bosworth), Nov 14, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Session Records (Nell Painter and Brenda Silver), Dec 5, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Session Records (Louise DeSalvo and Carol Stanger), Feb 6, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Session Records (Beth Diefendorf and Glenn Shafer), Mar 13, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Session Records (Meena Alexander and Paula Giddings), Apr 10, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Session Records (Kathleen Brady and Honor Moore), May 8, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Session Records (Jill Johnston and Suzannah Lessard), Oct 2, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Session Records (Blanche Wiesen Cook), Nov 6, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Session Records (Emily Mann), Dec 11, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Session Records (Honor Moore), Feb 5, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Session Records (Joan Acocella and Susan Hallgarth), Mar 11, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Session Records (Liz Harlan), Apr 6, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Session Records (Louise DeSalvo), May 13, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Session Records, Oct 7, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Session Records (Christina Baker and Christina Baker Kline), Dec 2, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Session Records (Elizabeth Brunazzi and Bell Chevigny), Jan 13, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Session Records (Susan Hertog and Stacy Schiff), Feb 3, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Session Records (Joanne Grant and Linda Reed), Mar 3, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Session Records (Margaret Gibson and Stephanie Strickland), Apr 14, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Session Records (Betty Boyd Caroli and Nancy Rubin), May 5, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Session Records (Norah Chase and Alix Kates Shulman), Oct 6, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Session Records (Ed McCoyd and Lisa Paddock), Nov 3, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Session Records (Claire Coss and Judith Sloan), Dec 8, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Session Records (Louise Bernikow and Jane Marcus), Jan 5, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Session Records (Bell Chevigny and Noel Riley Fitch), Feb 2, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Session Records (Gail Levin and Patricia Valenti), Mar 2, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Session Records (Nancy Kline and Brenda Wineapple), Apr 6, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Session Records (Dorothy Kaufman and Pat Laurence), May 4, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Session Records, Oct 5, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Session Records (Dorothy O. Helly and Polly Howells), Nov 2, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Session Records (Shareen Brysac, Blanche Weisen Cook, Dona Munker, and Ellen Schrecker), Dec 7, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Session Records (Patty O’Toole), Jan 11, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Session Records (Sydney Ladensohn Stern and Judith Hennessee), Feb 8, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Session Records (Betty Caroli and Carol Stanger), Mar 8, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Session Records (Elizabeth Brunazzi, Blanche Weisen Cook, and Ellen Schrecker), Apr 12, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Session Records (Kathy Chamberlain and Cheryl Torsney), May 3, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Session Records (Barbara Horn), Oct 4, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Session Records (Alexandra Johnson and Molly Vaux), Nov 1, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Session Records (Lois Beachy Underhill), Dec 6, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Session Records (Nancy Kline and Carol Stanger), Jan 10, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Session Records (Joyce Seltzer and Jane von Mehren), Feb 7, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Session Records (Harriet Alonso and Barbara McManus), Mar 6, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Session Records (Carole Klein and Marion Meade), Apr 3, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Session Records (Carolyn Heilbrun), May 1, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Session Records (Constance Rosenblum and Eve Golden), Oct 2, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Session Records (Susan Brownmiller and Donez Xiques), Nov 6, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Session Records (Christine Stansell), Dec 4, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Session Records (Deborah Gorham and Joanne Grant), Jan 7, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Session Records (Aileen Christianson), Feb 5, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Session Records (Rachel Brownstein and Dana Heller), Mar 5, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Session Records (Anne M. Wyatt-Brown), May 7, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Session Records (Adrienne Block and Rachel Brownstein), Oct 1, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Session Records (Joyce C. Harte and Wendy Orange), Nov 5, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Session Records (Elizabeth Brunazzi and Sherry Gorelick), Dec 3, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Session Records (Betsy Prioleau and Nancy Schoenberger), Jan 7, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Session Records (Meena Alexander and Flavia Alaya), Feb 4, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Session Records (Gail Hornstein), Mar 4, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Session Records (Dona Munker), Apr 8, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Session Records (Joanne Grant and Carla Peterson), May 13, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Session Records (Jill Norgren), May 5, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Session Records (Michael Nash), Dec 1, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Session Records (Victoria Olsen), Feb 2, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Session Records (Jennifer Fleishner and Diane Jacobs), Mar 1, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 37)